A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of David Arnold FA542
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of David Arnold
1971-1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Arnold, David D., 1952-
Ford Foundation
FA542
2.62 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 3 series:
1. Subject Files, 1971-1990
2. Speeches, 1990
3. Trip Files, 1985-1991
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains subject files, with a small selection of Speeches and trip records.
Biographical / Historical
David Arnold is a foundation executive who worked at the Ford Foundation from 1984 to 1997. In 2011, he was appointed President of the Asia Foundation.
Arnold joined the Ford Foundation in 1984 as a Program Officer in the Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG), Governance and Public Policy (GPP) unit. He was appointed GPP Deputy Director in 1987, and then, in 1991, he became the Foundation's Representative for India, Nepal, and Sri Lanka at the Foundation's New Delhi, India office.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Arnold worked as a Program Budget Analyst with the Michigan Department of Labor. He started in this position in 1975, and then, in 1977, he relocated to Washington D.C. where he had positions at the National Governors' Association and the Coalition of Northeastern Governors.
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1997, Arnold served as Executive Vice President of the Institute of International Education (IIE). He then became President of The American University in Cairo in 2003 and stayed in that position until joining the Asia Foundation in 2011 as President.
Arnold earned a Bachelor's Degree from the University of Michigan and a Master's Degree in public administration from Michigan State University.
- Subject Files, 1971-1990; I
  - American Electoral System, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Area Studies Project, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Foundation Grant Making - Economic Policy by Niahm Reilly, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Task Force - Growth, Development and Employment, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Discussion Paper - Improving American Governance, 1985 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Economic Policy Development Papers, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Governance in Chile, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Governance and Public Policy Program for the Philippines, 1986 December (Box 1)
  - Governance and Public Policy Program History, 1975-1983 (Box 1)
  - David P Arnold - Program Paper, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Governance and Public Policy Paper, 1989 May (Box 1)
  - Program Support Budget FY 1991, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Developmental Country Program - A Focus on Africa, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Governance and Public Policy Program Appropriations FY 1982, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Governance Program, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Greater Washington Research Center (McNamara Task Force), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Indian Health Papers, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Local Governance in Francophone West Africa, 1990 October (Box 1)
  - Political Dimensions of NGO Expansion in Africa, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Programming for Democratic Governance and Public Policy in Eastern and Southern Africa, 1990 January 2 (Box 1)
  - Program Papers Eastern and Southern Africa, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Program Support of Parliamentary Practice in Soviet Union and Eastern and Central Europe, 1990 May (Box 1)
  - Public Policy Think Tanks and Affirmative Action -- Working File, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Public Policy Background Papers, 1971-1989 (Box 1)
  - Public Policy in Latin America, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Don Robinson Consultancy -- Constitutional Bicentennial, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Social Welfare Reform, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Staff Workshop on Human Rights, 1987 January 18-22 (Box 1)
  - Think Tank Reports - Peter Yu, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Youth Service - Memorandum to Franklin Thomas, 1989 (Box 1)
- Speeches, 1990; II
  - Michigan Speech, 1990 April (Box 2)
  - Small Business Speech (Box 2)
- Trip Files, 1985-1991; III
  - Budapest Trip, 1990 January (Box 2)
  - Manila Philippines Trip File, 1991 January 27-February 3 (Box 2)
  - Moskow Trip, 1990 March (Box 2)
  - Poland Trip, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Washington Trip, 1990 January 16 (Box 2)
  - Wingspread Conference - Racine WI, 1985 November 3-5 (Box 2)
  - Vienna Planning Meeting, 1990 May (Box 2)
  - Zimbabwe Trip, 1990 (Box 2)